# THOMAS KEYES

#### **PROFILE**

#### Name

Thomas Keyes

#### **Address**

633 Lark Meadow Dr. Knoxville, TN 37934,

#### Phone

865 809 8966

#### Email

tkeyes1@vols.utk.edu

#### Website

www.linkedin.com/in/thomas-keyes

www.github.com/tkeyes25

# **OBJECTIVE**

I am seeking to learn new technologies and development strategies while developing exciting products that push toward a company's goal. As a Junior at the University of Tennessee majoring in Computer Science with a minor in Engineering Entrepreneurship, I have over two years experience and am ready for a bold, new challenge.

\*References available upon request

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Mar 2018 - Aug 2018 Eaton Corporation — Knoxville, TN

Programming Intern

- Created 'smart' breakers with engineering team that communicate with customers.
- · Updated 3-year-old iOS app and dependencies to install 'smart' breakers.
- · Reduced GitHub issues for iOS app and 'smart' breaker repositories, saving hundreds of hours debugging.

May 2017 - Aug 2017 vCAD, Inc. — Knoxville, TN

Quality Assurance Testing Intern

- · Developed a "Command Center" representing real-time user data allowing dataanalysts to analyze customer behavior immeasurably faster.
- · Performed alongside development team to brainstorm ideas, solve technical problems, and test products.

## **EDUCATION**

Graduation May of 2020

#### Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Tickle College of Engineering

University of Tennessee, Knoxville, GPA: 3.78, Magnum Cum Laude Major: Computer Science Minor: Engineering Entrepreneurship

Coursework: Software Engineering, Algorithms/Data Structures, Operating Systems, Engineering Entrepreneurship

#### LEADERSHIP

Aug 2017 - Present

#### **Integrated Business and Engineering Program**

- · Selected as one of 20 students from Tickle College of Engineering and Haslam College
- · Received specialized training in leadership, systematic thinking, professionalism and communication with real-world projects towards local businesses.

### RESEARCH/PROJECTS

Aug 2018 - Present

#### **Human Aspects of Software Engineering**

Undergraduate Research Assistant

· Researching and building tools and plugins to make developers more productive

# Aug 2018 - Dec 2018 Collaborative Playlist Web Application

· Constructed a multimedia web app to enhance community playlist experience with features such as a carousel of various media and viewing other users' playlist.

June 2018 - Dec 2018 Knoxville Golf Website

Lead Developer

· Built personal web application with CRUD functionalities for Knoxville's local golf courses and reviews.

# ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017 Local Motors Semester Project

Student Team with Integrated Business and Engineering Program

 Evaluated stakeholder requirements and proposed ideals solutions to Local Motors new bus stop for their autonomous bus Olli.

Aug 2016 - Present

#### Clubs/Organizations

· HackUTK, VolHacks, utkML, VolCourt, Anderson Center for Entrepreneurship & Innovation, RUF Ministry Team, Knoxville Area Rescue Ministry Volunteer

# LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

- Swift, C/C++, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, some experience with Java, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express.js, Realm Database
- · Git, GitHub, Xcode, Firebase, Fastlane (Automation for mobile), Visual Studio Code, Atom, Slack, Outlook